{"tossups": [{"question": "The speaker of one of these poems laments, \u201cThat time of year thou mayst in me behold\u201d beseeching the reader in its final line \u201cTo love that well which thou must leave ere long.\u201d Phrases such as \u201cthe master-mistress of my passion\u201d and \u201cunfolding his imprison'd pride\u201d from these poems have fueled speculation that their author was bisexual. The speaker concludes that \u201cAll losses are restored and sorrows end\u201d in one of these poems, and in another, the speaker claims that if he is mistaken, \u201c[He] never writ, nor no man ever loved.\u201d That poem states (*) \u201cLove is not love / Which alters when it alteration finds.\u201d The line \u201cSo long lives this, and gives life to thee,\u201d ends the most famous of these poems, 27 of which are about the Dark Lady. For 10 points, name this collection of 14-line poems, the most famous of which begins \u201cShall I compare thee to a summer\u2019s day?\u201d", "answer": "sonnets by William Shakespeare [or equivalents; prompt on partial answers, such as sonnets or poems by Shakespeare]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>sonnets by William Shakespeare</u></b> [ or equivalents; prompt on <u>partial answers, such as sonnets</u> or <u>poems by Shakespeare</u>]", "acceptable": ["sonnets by William Shakespeare"], "promptable": ["partial answers, such as sonnets", "poems by Shakespeare"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character\u2019s father fictitiously loaned money to a town to be repaid over time. While discussing this character, a judge asks, \"will you accuse a lady to her face of smelling bad?\" causing her neighbors to \u201c[begin] to feel sorry for her.\u201d This character is forced to give the corpse of her father to the Board of Aldermen. This character falls in love with a man who frequently drinks at the Elks Club and worked up North before travelling to the fictional town of (*) Jefferson. This woman, whose black servant Tobe brings her groceries, goes out once in her story to buy arsenic, using it to kill Homer Barron. For 10 points, name this character, the old woman who keeps Homer\u2019s dead body in a bedroom above the stairs in a short story by William Faulkner.", "answer": "Emily Grierson [accept either; accept \u201cA Rose for Emily\u201d]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Emily Grierson</u></b> [accept <b><u>either</u></b>; accept <b><u>\u201cA Rose for Emily\u201d</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Emily Grierson", "either", "\u201cA Rose for Emily\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of one poem by this author meets Captain One, Motherth, Jesus, and Don Quixote. That protagonist then travels down the Nile and is killed by an iceberg in Antarctica. The title character of another work by this author calls a hotel manager Bouboulina and calls himself Canavaro. A widow in that work is stoned and decapitated after spending the night with the narrator. This author wrote a poem that contains (*) 33,333 17-syllable verses and is a \u201cmodern sequel\u201d to an ancient poem. The title character of one of this man\u2019s novels stares at the narrator, who is about to begin reading Dante\u2019s Divine Comedy, through a glass window. That title character eventually befriends the narrator and leads him to Madame Hortense\u2019s Hotel. The Odyssey: A Modern Sequel is by, for 10 points, what author of Zorba the Greek?", "answer": "Nikos Kazantzakis", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Nikos <b><u>Kazantzakis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nikos Kazantzakis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel dreams about walking into the Golden Gate Park and seeing children play hopscotch. In one scene in this novel, the protagonist stares at a picture of James Clerk Maxwell to try and use the Nefastis machine. Vittorio tells Niccolo about the Lost Guard of Faggio in a fictional play written by Richard Wharfinger within this novel. Randolph Driblette directs a production of that play, (*) The Courier\u2019s Tragedy. The protagonist of this novel sees the word \u201cW.A.S.T.E.\u201d written in a bathroom at the Scope. A lawyer named Metzger helps the protagonist execute the estate of Pierce Inverarity in this novel, in which a secretive postal service organization is symbolized by a muted post horn. Trystero is investigated by Oedipa Maas in, for 10 points, what novel by Thomas Pynchon?", "answer": "The Crying of Lot 49", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Crying of Lot 49</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Crying of Lot 49"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a series of lectures, Vladimir Nabokov argued that this character follows his author\u2019s \u201cformula\u201d and begins living \u201cLife with a capital L\u201d at the end of the work in which he appears. This character is respected for his ability to \u201ccompletely exclud[e] his personal opinion of the matter,\u201d leading him to be promoted to a city position and use the extra money earned to furnish a new house. This character has a recurring dream that ends with \u201csome force\u201d that shoves him through a sack. This character loses his love of playing (*) whist after falling off of a step ladder while hanging curtains. This character\u2019s caretaker, Gerasim, remarks \u201ceveryone dies someday\u201d at his funeral, which was announced by his friend Pyotr Ivanovich to a group of lawyers he worked with. For 10 points, name this title character of a Leo Tolstoy novella.", "answer": "Ivan Ilyich [accept either; accept The Death of Ivan Ilyich]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ivan Ilyich</u></b> [accept <b><u>either</u></b>; accept <b><u>The Death of Ivan Ilyich</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Ivan Ilyich", "either", "The Death of Ivan Ilyich"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonists of this text escape from their flammable house by hiring a miner who digs out a tunnel. The wife of a blind man in this text blindfolds herself to feel the pain he does. A stray dog accompanies a character in this text to the top of a mountain and reveals himself to be the god of death. One character in this text loses a (*) dice game and is forced to retire to a forest with his family. A character in this text attempts to disrobe Draupadi but fails when a god magically extends the cloth. This text follows the legendary Kurukshetra War, in which Krishna freezes time to discuss Arjuna\u2019s duty as a Kshatriya. For 10 points, name this Hindu epic about the clash between the Pandavas and Kauravas which includes the Bhagavad Gita in its sixth book.", "answer": "Mahabharata", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mahabharata</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Mahabharata"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this play, two characters discuss combinations of removing two paws from two cats, including one where one cat has six and the other has none. The protagonist of this play arrives late to work, but his boss, Mr. Papillon, does not notice because he is conversing with another character. That character, Botard, insists he does not \"need [journalists] to tell [him] what to think\" and says he both despises religion and esteems it highly. Later in this play, a woman quietly claims, (*) \"They're like gods\" about a crowd in the street below a window. That character, Daisy, is the love interest of another character in this play who loudly proclaims, \"I'm not capitulating!\" to a sickness that turned his friend Jean's skin green and formed a bump on his head. For 10 points, every character but Berenger transforms into the title animal of what play by Eugene Ionesco?", "answer": "Rhinoceros", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rhinoceros</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rhinoceros"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this city, Father Butler scolds Leo Dillon for reading fictional adventure stories rather than his Roman History material. Before going to an event in this city wished to not be some \u201cFreemason Affair,\u201d a character is asked if he recalls a poem titled for a certain people\u2019s \u201cFarewell To Steed.\u201d In one story set in this city, Ignatius Gallaher waits at a bar for an old friend named Little Chandler, who makes his baby cry by reading a Byron poem aloud. Two youths learn about the death of (*) Father Flynn in this city, the setting of stories such as \u201cA Little Cloud.\u201d An eastern-themed bazaar in this city serves as the title setting of one short story, while another story set here concludes with Gabriel Conroy imagining snow falling on the grave of Michael Furey, one of \u201cThe Dead.\u201d For 10 points, name this city, the namesake of a James Joyce collection of short stories.", "answer": "Dublin, Ireland [accept Dubliners]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Dublin, Ireland</u></b> [accept <b><u>Dubliners</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Dublin, Ireland", "Dubliners"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of a novel first looks at these things after she receives Graham Crackers and states \u201cI like Jane Withers\u201d while listening to a story about a Christmas doll. The last chapter of a novel titled for these things shows a character conversing with an imaginary friend who suggests \u201cwe could go outside and play I guess.\u201d One character is reminded of these features after a cat is thrown into a radiator, and unwittingly kills a dog named Bob while trying to acquire them. These features title a novel that opens with the arrival of (*) Henry Washington, and Maureen Peal's presence intensifies the protagonist\u2019s desire for them. Claudia narrates that novel, in which the protagonist idolizes these features on a Shirley Temple mug. For 10 points, name these facial features desired by Pecola Breedlove in a Toni Morrison novel.", "answer": "blue eyes [accept The Bluest Eye; prompt on any answer mentioning eyes without including the word \u201cblue\u201d]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>blue eyes</u></b> [accept <b><u>The Bluest Eye</u></b>; prompt on <u>any answer mentioning eyes without including the word \u201cblue\u201d</u>]", "acceptable": ["blue eyes", "The Bluest Eye"], "promptable": ["any answer mentioning eyes without including the word \u201cblue\u201d"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, two \u201cbedwetters\u201d must serve punishment by trading places on bunkers each night, becoming drenched by the other\u2019s urine. Three characters in this novel \u201csmile bitterly\u201d after receiving a note that describes them as \u201cIron Youth.\u201d This novel\u2019s protagonist feels a sense of \u201cstrangeness\u201d after arriving home and finding out that his mother is dying of cancer. Three French women are visited by (*) Lee and Kropp in this novel, whose protagonist feels guilty after ending the life of the printer Gerard Duval. Kat aids the main characters of this novel, one of whom named Muller inherits Kemmerich\u2019s boots after he dies. Paul Baumer joins German forces fighting World War One in, For 10 points, what novel by Erich Maria Remarque?", "answer": "All Quiet on the Western Front", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>All Quiet on the Western Front</u></b>", "acceptable": ["All Quiet on the Western Front"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The biographer of this poem\u2019s author, Paul Mariani, said that this poem \"wears a deliberately commonplace costume\" and was most likely written about African-American traditions at funeral wakes. According to Elizabeth Bishop, this poem\u2019s author drew inspiration from Cuban factory workers to write this poem\u2019s opening lines. This poem describes a \u201cdresser of deal\u201d and asks to \u201cLet the lamp (*) affix its beam,\u201d to \u201cshow how cold she is, and dumb.\u201d This poem instructs, \u201clet the boys / Bring flowers in last month's newspapers\u201d and opens with \u201cCall the roller of big cigars\u201d and \u201cbid him whip / In kitchen cups concupiscent curds.\u201d For 10 points, the creation of the title dessert is described in what poem by Wallace Stevens?", "answer": "\u201cThe Emperor of Ice Cream\u201d", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cThe Emperor of Ice Cream\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cThe Emperor of Ice Cream\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of one novel by this author paints Pythoness at Tripod, which depicts a crazy cat lady who is actually his sister. Don Lethbridge later helps that protagonist create a magnum opus. In another novel by this author, Mr. Judd attends a garden party held by Belle Radclyffe twenty years after the title protagonist disappears. This author wrote about the prostitute Nance Lightfoot, who is loved by the adopted brother of Rhoda in one novel, while another character created by this man is financed by Mr. (*) Bonner. Hurtle Duffield is adopted by the Courtneys in one of this man\u2019s novels, and in another he wrote about a title German explorer who dies during a journey into the Outback. For 10 points, name this Australian author of The Vivisector and Voss.", "answer": "Patrick Victor Martindale White", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Patrick Victor Martindale <b><u>White</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Patrick Victor Martindale White"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An essay about this character describes a man who terrorized the author in his childhood by taking away \u201cballs, bats, spinning tops, and marbles.\u201d The work this character appears in opens with him being asked to \u201cturn on the light\u201d after an alarm sounds a loud \u201cBrrring!\u201d An essay describing five people from the author\u2019s childhood is titled for how this man \u201cWas Born.\u201d This character frightens his sister by killing a (*) rat with a skillet in \u201cFear,\u201d the first section of the novel in which he appears. This man visits Ernie\u2019s Kitchen Shack and famously signs a ransom note with the word \u201cReds.\u201d Jan Erlorne hires attorney Boris Max to defend this character for the murder of his girlfriend, Bessie Mears, and his employer\u2019s daughter, Mary Dalton. For 10 points, name this protagonist of Richard Wright\u2019s novel Native Son.", "answer": "Bigger Thomas [accept either]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bigger Thomas</u></b> [accept <b><u>either</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Bigger Thomas", "either"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book includes a story of a man who buys every almond from a market because his daughter ate some without paying. In this book, the author describes a volatile political climate that began with American drone strikes in 2004. The author of this book recounts moving to Shangla while writing under the pseudonym \"Gul Mukai\" for a BBC blog. Later, the author explains how her family did not own passports to fly with her to (*) Queen Elizabeth Hospital in Birmingham for a facial nerve surgery. The main conflict of this autobiographical work erupts on October 9, 2012, where the author is shot while returning from a Pakistan Studies exam. For 10 points, what autobiography includes events from the life of \"the girl who fought for education\" against the Taliban?", "answer": "I Am Malala: The Girl Who Stood Up for Education and Was Shot by the Taliban [prompt on Malala Yousafzai\u2019s autobiography or similar]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>I Am Malala: The Girl Who Stood Up for Education and Was Shot by the Taliban</u></b> [prompt on <u>Malala Yousafzai\u2019s autobiography</u> or <u>similar</u>]", "acceptable": ["I Am Malala: The Girl Who Stood Up for Education and Was Shot by the Taliban"], "promptable": ["Malala Yousafzai\u2019s autobiography", "similar"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poem by this author criticizes \u201cEgnatius, made a gentleman by a bushy beard / And teeth brushed with Spanish urine.\u201d An epyllion by this author describes the marriage of Peleus and Thetis and the abandonment of Ariadne by Theseus. One poem by this author tries to cope with the death of one whom \u201cFortune has carried\u2026 away from me.\u201d Another poem by this author threatens to sodomize Aurelius and Furius and is called (*) Carmen 16. This author is upset that his \u201cgirlfriend\u2019s little swollen eyes are red with weeping\u201d after the death of her pet sparrow. One poem by this author ends with \u201chail and farewell\u201d or \u201cave atque vale.\u201d Clodia was believed to be the true identity of a dedicatee of many of this author\u2019s poems. For 10 points, name this Roman poet who dedicated many poems to his lover Lesbia.", "answer": "Gaius Valerius Catullus", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Gaius Valerius <b><u>Catullus</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Gaius Valerius Catullus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Description acceptable. The heaviest one of these characters must be carried by the others after falling into a river and falling asleep. These characters originally doubt the ability of a companion to be a \"burglar,\" who later steals a cup from another character. A character who accompanies this group saves them by mimicking their voices until three vagabonds turn to stone, and a leader of these characters finds a sword called (*) Orcrist. These characters float down barrels to reach Lake Town, which is later burned down. The leader of these characters refuses to offer any compensation to the rest of them, despite their assistance in killing Smaug, causing them to attack each other in the Battle of Five Armies before uniting against an army of goblins. For 10 points, what group of thirteen characters does Bilbo Baggins accompany to the Lonely Mountain?", "answer": "dwarves from The Hobbit [accept Thorin and Company; prompt on dwarves by asking \u201cin what book?\u201d; do not accept or prompt on any Lord of the Rings references]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>dwarves from The Hobbit</u></b> [accept <b><u>Thorin and Company</u></b>; prompt on <u>dwarves by asking \u201cin what book?\u201d</u>; do not accept or prompt on \"any Lord of the Rings references\"]", "acceptable": ["dwarves from The Hobbit", "Thorin and Company"], "promptable": ["dwarves by asking \u201cin what book?\u201d"], "rejectable": ["any Lord of the Rings references"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author discusses whether aliens' sins are covered by Jesus's sacrifice in a case against the traditional Christian God. In this author\u2019s argument against reconciliation with an enemy, he quotes Milton's idea that it is not possible \"where wounds of deadly hate have pierced so deep,\" and explains that every attempt at peace has been ignored. This author wrote another work, the best-selling title in American history, which discusses the relationship between a (*) small island and a continent. This author later defended the French Revolution in Rights of Man. In another work, this author describes \"crowned ruffians\" and warned its readers not to be \"summer soldier[s] during \"the times that try men's souls.\" For 10 points, what influential author wrote pamphlets such as The American Crisis and Common Sense?", "answer": "Thomas Paine", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Thomas <b><u>Paine</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Thomas Paine"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A \u201clyric tragic episode\u201d found in a poem from this country describes a woman\u2019s wishes to be exiled to Syria or Libya, and it also notes Monsayeed\u2019s exploits to help the protagonist. A poet from this country created works such as Mensagem, which famously described myth as \u201cthe nothing that is all.\u201d That author from this country created a \u201cfactless autobiography\u201d of one of his many (*) heteronyms catalogued in The Book of the Disquiet. A monster named Adamastor captures the protagonists of an epic poem from this country, which contain scenes depicting Bacchus and Venus debating on guiding a ship towards Calicut. Fernando Pessoa and Lu\u00eds de Cam\u00f5es hailed from, for 10 points, what country home to the hero of The Lusiads, Vasco de Gama?", "answer": "Portugal", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Portugal</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Portugal"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A writer with this surname wrote of the Roman murder trial of a man who kills his wife and her parents in a 21,000 line verse novel. That author with this surname ended a poem with the line \u201cAgain the Cousin's whistle!\u201d while describing a \u201cfaultless\u201d artist. Another writer with this surname wrote of children in mines who weep, \u201cwe are weary, / And we cannot run or leap\u201d in \u201cThe Cry of the Children.\u201d An author with this surname remarks of a woman \u201cLooking as if she were alive\u201d after being painted by (*) Fra Pandolf. That writer with this surname wrote \u201cGather the north flowers to complete the south,\u201d in a poem that opens \u201cYes, call me by my pet-name!\u201d For 10 points, name this surname shared by a wife who asked, \u201cHow do I love thee? Let me count the ways,\" and her husband, the author of \u201cMy Last Duchess.\u201d", "answer": "Browning [accept Robert Browning or Elizabeth Barrett Browning; prompt on Moulton-Barrett]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Browning</u></b> [accept <b><u>Robert Browning</u></b> or <b><u>Elizabeth Barrett Browning</u></b>; prompt on <u>Moulton-Barrett</u>]", "acceptable": ["Browning", "Robert Browning", "Elizabeth Barrett Browning"], "promptable": ["Moulton-Barrett"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character created by this author discusses a 1920 experiment conducted on an ape by Kohler during a lecture at Appleton College. In a novel by this author, a character is attacked with spitballs when attempting to view the play Sunset at the Globe Salon, and earlier claims that he has \u201csolved the problem of sex rather well.\u201d A doctor identifies the protagonist as \u201cCM\u201d in a novel by this author, and in another the protagonist begins an affair with the dog caretaker (*) Bev Shaw. The protagonist earlier sleeps with the prostitute Soraya in that novel, and his daughter Lucy is raped by three robbers. The activist Elizabeth Costello was created by this author, who wrote about a harelipped man transporting his sick mother Anna to Prince Albert. For 10 points, name this author of The Life and Times of Michael K, who wrote about Professor David Lurie\u2019s affair with Melanie Issacs in Disgrace.", "answer": "J. M. Coetzee [or John Maxwell Coetzee]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "J. M. <b><u>Coetzee</u></b> [or <b><u>John Maxwell Coetzee</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["J. M. Coetzee", "John Maxwell Coetzee"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}